welcome to the machine learning for students series
欢迎大家来到学生机器学习系列
I'll be your teacher
我是你们的老师
today and we're going to be learning
今天 我们将要学习
about image classifiers are you ready
关于图像分类器的知识 你准备好了吗
let's go so what is image classification
让我们开始吧 图像分类是什么呢
well let's start with the basics
就让我们从基础开始吧
it's a subfield of computer vision and
它是计算机视觉的子场
what it does is it helps a computer
它的作用是帮助计算机
learn how to distinguish between
学习如何区分
different objects like our furry friends
不同的对象 就像区分我们毛茸茸的朋友
here the dog and the cat
一个是猫一个是狗
so where did image classification come from
所以图像分类来自何处呢
that's an excellent question
这是一个很好的问题
it's actually been around since the rise
它实际上是自电脑兴起以来
of computers but it hasn't really been
就一直存在 但它确实没有
that good now in 2012 everything changed
很好 但是现在2012年了 一切都改变啦
because of Professor Gregory
因为格雷戈里教授
he proposed using convolutional neural
他提出使用卷积神经网络
networks to classify images
网络对图像进行分类
now that might sound like a scary word to you
可能现在听起来这是一个可怕的词
but it's not I promise what it was able to
但我保证它不是 它能够
do was classify images of 85% accuracy
对图像进行分类 精确度高达85%
way better than it's ever been done
比以往任何方式都要好
before in the past and it's completely
这完全是
revolutionized machine learning now
彻底改变了机器学习
let's get into the history of image
让我们更深入了解图像分类
classification a little more
的历史
i am going to bring you into the groovy 70s here a
首先我们来看看70年代的图像分类
starter back in the 70s developers used
70年代第一批开发人员
to use nested Nets and very specifically
使用嵌套网络
to find parameters of images to classify them
找到要分类的图像的参数 然后将其分类
the assumption was that everything
他们的假设就是一切
looked the same we know that that's not true
看起来是一样的  我们知道这是不对的
not every fish in the ocean looks the same
不是海洋中的每条鱼都看起来都是一样的
right well that's where
这就是
convolutional neural networks came in
卷积神经网络开始进入的时刻了
we're gonna fast forward into the 90s
我们要快进到90年代
convolutional neural networks were able be used
卷积神经网络能够在此时被使用了
now fast forward again until
现在再次快进到
2012 an image net that changed all the rules
2012年 图像网改变了一切
it gave rise to a whole new world
它打开了深度学习的
of deep learning kind of like how
新世界 就好像现在
Michael Jordan changed basketball or how
迈克尔乔丹改变了篮球 或者
Babe Ruth changed baseball or Tom Brady
贝比·鲁斯改变了棒球 又像是汤姆·布拉迪
changed football at this point I hope
改变了足球 我希望在这一点上改变足球
you're wondering how image
你一定想知道如何图像分类
classification actually works well
分类是怎么运作的吧
let's start diving into it first it's really
让我们开始开始深入学习它吧
first it's really based on a lot of data and computational power
首先 它是基于大量数据和计算能力
so remember how I was just talking
大家还记得我说的在
about in the 70s we didn't have the power
70年代我们还没有这样的能力
we needed to really do image
去做到真正的图像
classification right well we definitely
分类 而现在我们能做到了
image classification is
图像分类是属于
supervised learning classification now
监督学习分类的
that might sound a little intimidating
这可能听起来有点令人生畏
but I promise you it's not
但我向你保证它并没有那么可怕
I'm going to go ahead and break it down what it does
我们继续往下 我们来一点点学习
is it takes a lot of labeled images and
首先 它需要大量的标记图像
then it puts those through an input layer
然后把图像放到输入层
and after that it moves into some
然后再放到
hidden layers where the algorithm learns
隐藏层 在此算法会学习分析
a little bit about the images maybe what
图像 可能是图像的颜色
color it is maybe what shape it is and
可能是它的形状
then it puts it into the output layer
然后再把图像放入输出层
and tells you what the image actually is
并告诉你图像是什么
so if we're thinking about it in terms
所以 如果我们想要得到
of a dog or a cat
一只狗或一只猫
it'll take thousands and thousands of
它实际上需要成千上万的
images of dogs and a cat it'll put it
狗和猫的图像 将图像
into this input layer the algorithm then
放置输入层 然后算法会学习
learns what features about dogs and cats
了解狗和猫的特征来知道
really make a dog and a cat a dog and a cat
到底是什么特征让狗和猫之所以成为狗和猫
and then it'll tell you whether or not
然后它会告诉你输入的图片到底
the image is a dog and  a cat now
是不是狗和猫
once ouralgorithm has learned we can use it to
一旦算法学会了如何分析 我们就可以用它来
predict images that has never seen before
分析预测从未见过的图像
so you can give it a whole bunch
你可以给它一大堆
of pictures of your own dog and your own cat
你自己的狗和猫的图片
and ask it hey is this a dog or a cat
问它这是一只狗还是一只猫
and it'll let you know
它会告诉你答案
so now that you know how image classification works
现在你已经知道图像分类是如何工作的
let's talk about some of the problems
让我们来看看它能解决的
that it's solving this is very exciting
的问题吧 真是太令人兴奋啦
stuff it's doing facial detection a lot
它可以用于面部检测
of you might have seen this on Facebook
你可能在Facebook上看过这个了
you've probably encountered it before
你可能已经用过它了
where your friends are pre-selected for
在你最开始选择好友的时候
you and Facebook actually tells you
Facebook会告诉你
who's in a picture I think that's really
照片里的人是谁 真是太酷啦
and that's all image classification
这就是图像分类的作用哦
self-driving cars use image classification
图像分类也应用在自动驾驶汽车
because they need to know
因为它们需要知道
what the difference is between a stop
停止符号和人之间
sign and a person running into a car
的区别
they're almost entirely based on image classification
这几乎完全依靠于图像分类
because they actually
因为它们
need to see the world around them to
需要看到它们周围的世界才能
drive and we're also using facial recognition
驾驶 我们也将面部识别
in security imagine getting
应用于安保 想象一下你
into a house or getting into some sort
进入一件房子或参加一个
of business with a picture of your face
活动  里面是有你人脸照片的
it's being used right now in real time
现在这个技术正在被实时使用
to make your world even more secure so
让我们的世界变得更加安全
let's talk about some more uses now
现在我来谈谈更多的用途
I know that we just went over three
我知道我们刚刚已经介绍了三个
but this is such exciting stuff and there's
但这是真的是令人兴奋的东西 而且它还有
so much out there that we need to talk
很多其他的用途 我们赶紧来看看
about even more of it let's talk about
它的其他用途吧
plant disease identification
植物病害识别
we're using image
我们正在使用图像
recognition to be able to identify
识别来判断
whether or not a plant has disease that
植物是否感染病害
means that biologists out there are able
这意味着生物学家可以
to quickly identify which disease the
更快速确定植物感染了
plant has and better come up with
什么病害并想出相应的
approaches you choose for it
治疗方法
you're using smart cameras and smart homes that
智能相机和智能家居
can tell you who's at your door now
可以告诉你现在谁在你家门口
imagine if you were home the doorbell
想象一下 如果家门铃
rang and the house immediately said hey
一响起 房子马上可以告诉你
grandma's at the front door how great would that be
是奶奶在前门 这真是太棒了呀
we've also used image
我们也将图像
recognition in cancer detection what's
识别应用于癌症检测
what's really interesting about this example is
有趣的是
that image recognition was able to find
图像识别能够找到一些
cancer markers that real human
癌症标志物 然而
scientists have missed it found things
这些标志物科学家们却没有找到 所以它能够找到
about cancer that we didn't even know
我们人类所不知道的关于癌症的东西
now beyond all those examples I just
除了刚刚我的提到的这些例子
gave let's talk about how image
现在让我们谈谈图像
classification is empowering the future
分类如何使机器人变得
of robotics image classification is the
更加强大 图像分类是
basic tool robotics uses to interact
机器人使用的基本工具 它用于与
with the world around it a robot doesn't
周围的世界交流 机器人不是
really have eyes so how does it know
真的有眼睛 所以它无法知道
what's around well through image
周围的世界 但是通过图像
classification it has all of those
分类 它可以有所有的
trained models inside of it so that it
训练模型 所以当它看到
knows when it sees a human or animal or
人或动物或
airplane or an alien or an insect what
飞机或外星人或昆虫的时候
those things actually are
它能知道是什么
how cool is that
真是太酷了
how does image classification work
图像分类是如何运作的呢
we're going to go into it into some detail
我们要来深入研究一些细节
what we have here is a convolutional
这里有一个卷积
neural network and that's what you see
神经网络 就是在
on the slide what it does is it takes a
幻灯片上的这个东西 它接收
bunch of label images of cats and dogs
一大堆猫和狗的标签图像
and it puts it into the input layer
并放入输入层中
that's what you see there on the bottom
这就是你在底部看到的东西
now all of those image go into what we
然后所有图像都将进入
call activated neurons those are those
激活神经元里 也就是那些
hidden layers that's where the
隐藏层 也就是在那里
algorithms trying to figure out what
算法试图分析得出
features the images that you gave it are
你输入图像的特征 比如
a cat and a dog it might use color it
是一只猫还是一只狗 它可能会用颜色
might use size it might use shape or
尺寸 形状或者
distance between the eyes
眼睛之间的距离来作为特征
we don't really know then after it's
这个我们真的不知道了 在进行
done all of that learning the image will
学习之后 图像的所有内容
come out into the output layer and the
会进入到输出层 然后
algorithms gonna let you know whether or
算法会告诉你你输入的图片
not it thinks the image is a dog or a cat
是不是猫或者狗
now this is called a deep neural
这被称为深度神经
network and this is
网络 这是
the latest and greatest in image classification
图像分类最新和最棒的地方了
once you have a trained
一旦你有一个训练完成的
model you can give the model a new image
模型 你可以给模型一个它之前从未见过的
that it's never seen before so if the
新的图像 比如这个
computers have never seen my dog or my
电脑从未见过我的狗或我的
cat before and I showed a picture of one
猫 现在我展示了一张照片
of them it's gonna tell me whether or
电脑会告诉我这是否
not it's my dog or my cat so what real
是我的狗或我的猫
what real companies use image classification well
所以真正的公司是怎么应用图像分类的呢
let's get into some examples Google uses
让我们来看看谷歌里的一些例子
image classification to help you search
图像分类可以以帮助更好地进行网络
the web it'll help you get to where you
搜索 它会帮助你更快地到达
need to go faster Tesla uses image
你的目的地 特斯拉使用图像
classifications to develop self-driving
分类来发展自驾
cars
汽车
Facebook uses image classification to
Facebook使用图像分类来
help you find which friends are in that
帮助你识别你刚刚拍的照片里的
picture you just took and Apple uses
朋友们是谁  苹果公司使用
image classification to help you make
图像分类来使
those emojis even more fun
表情符号变得更有趣
they actually track your face and make
它可以追踪你的脸 做出与
the same expressions that you do and
和你一样的表情
some of you might have actually used all
你们中的一些人可能已经用过了上述的所有
of these already and didn't even know it
但是却不知道这与图像分类有关
so what if you want to learn more about
如果您想了解更多信息关于
image classification in this exciting
图像分类的知识
field well we've given you three books
这里有三本书可以推荐给大家
here that we think are great you have
都是非常棒的书
image recognition and classification by
image recognition and classification（图像识别与分类）
Bahram Kavidi you have OpenCV by Gary Bradski
作者是Bahram Kavidi 还有Gary Bradski的 OpenCV
it's part of the O'Reilly series of books
它是O'Reilly系列丛书的一部分
and then you have computer vision
还有Computer Vision(计算机视觉)
by Richard Solinsky
作者是 Richard Szeliski
I'm sure you're wondering where can I find real examples
你是不是很想知道哪里可以找到图像分类应用的
of the power of image classification
真实的例子
well we have some here for you first
这里有一些例子 首先
let's talk about google's alphago
让我们谈谈谷歌的alphago吧
it beat the world's best go player now
它现在击败了世界上最好围棋手
if you don't know what go is
如果你不知道围棋到底是什么
it's considered the most nerdy game in the world
它被认为是世界上最最最书呆子气的游戏
there's actually more moves in the
围棋中可移动的招数比
game go then there are stars and atoms
宇宙里的星星和原子的数量还要多
in our universe and believe it or not
信不信由你
using image classification and other
然而 在使用图像分类和其他
machine learning techniques Google was
机器学习技术之后 谷歌
able to develop a program to beat the
能够制作一个程序来
best go player you can check out this
击败世界上最好的围棋手  你可以看看youtube上的
video here on YouTube to see it in action
视频
this next examples for all you
下一个例子是有关
gamers out there I don't know if any of
游戏玩家的 不知道大家有没有玩过
you guys play the Defense of the Ancients
守护遗迹（DOTA）
game online but you might think
但是你一定会想
it's
如果要
impossible for someone to actually be one
让电脑来模拟成为一个真的玩家
of the real world players using a
是不可能的
computer if you do you'd actually be
如果你也是这样觉得的 那你就
wrong
大错特错啦
OpenAI was able to develop an algorithm
OpenAI用图像分类设计了
using image classification that was able
一种算法 它能够
to beat one of the world's best defense of the ancient players
击败游戏中最好的防守
definitely check
如果你不信的话
out this youtube video if you want to
可以去youtube看一下这个视频
see that algorithm in action this next
来看看这个算法是怎么做到的
this next example is so exciting
下一个例子也超让人兴奋的
Saudi Arabia created its first
沙特阿拉伯创造了第一个
artificial intelligence citizen Sophia
人工智能公民索菲亚
she uses image classification to
她利用图像分类来
interact with the world around her
与她周围的世界互动
kind of like that movie I Robot where the
有点像电影I Robot（我，机器人）放的那样
robots were actually able to communicate
在电影中 机器人能够与人类沟通
with human beings now take a look at
如果你感兴趣的话
this video on YouTube if you want to see that in action
也可以上youtube看看这个视频
I want to thank you very
非常感谢大家
much for taking the time to learn about
能抽出时间学习
image classification with me today
图像分类的知识
I'm so excited that you're going to be
一想到大家以后会接受这些算法的训练
training these algorithms in a future
我就觉得很激动啦